Guide to the Ann Henshaw Gardiner Papers, 1723-1981 RL.00432
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographic Materials, 1860s-1960s
  - Family and Friends prints (2 of 2) (Box 22)
    - Silhouettes of Martha Jane Silver, Hiram Henshaw, David Henshaw, William Henshaw, circa 1900 (Box 22, Image RL00432-I-0021)
      Photograph is of silhouettes from late 18th and early 19th century.
    - Edward Claggett Williams, circa 1890 (Box 22, Image RL00432-I-0022)
    - Ann Henshaw Gardiner, circa 1905 (Box 22, Image RL00432-I-0023)
  - Family and Friends prints, circa 1900-1980 (Box 22)
  - Family and Friends: NITRATES, circa 1900-1980 (Box 43)
  - Family and Friends: Shepherd College, circa 1906; 1908 (Box 22)
  - Family and Friends: scrapbook album, 1910-1916 (Box 24)
    Includes nurse training at Wesson Maternity, Springfield MA
  - Family and Friends: Mabel and Francis Henshaw, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 22)
  - Family and Friends: Mabel and Francis Henshaw printing blocks, circa late 1800s (Box 25)
  - Family and Friends: Mabel and Francis Henshaw: NITRATES, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 43)
  - Family and Friends: Graves of Valley Virginia Henshaw and others, circa 1930s (Box 22)
  - Family and Friends: Graves of Valley Virginia Henshaw and others: NITRATES, circa 1930s (Box 43)
  - Historic buildings and bridges, Martinsburg, W. Va, 1887-circa 1930s (Box 22)
  - Historic buildings and bridges, Martinsburg, W. Va: NITRATES, 1887-circa 1930s (Box 43)
  - Historic maps and documents, circa 19th century (Box 22)
    Images are photographs or photographic copies of original maps and other dicuments.
  - Historic maps and documents: GLASS, circa 19th century (Box 23)
    Access note. Fragile materials in the form of glass plate images may need special assistance from staff. Contact Research Services for access.
  - Historic maps and documents: NITRATES, circa 19th century (Box 43)
  - Nursing: France, World War 1, 1917 (Box 22)
    Original nitrate negatives were scanned, then removed from this folder and discarded.
  - Nursing: France, World War 1: scrapbook album, 1917 (Box 39)
  - Nursing: scrapbook album, circa 1930s (Box 41)
  - Nursing: Duke, circa 1939-1940 (Box 22)
  - Nursing: Duke, circa 1939-1940 (Box 23)
  - Nursing: Duke, 1939 (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Nursing: Duke: NITRATES, circa 1939-1940 (Box 43)
  - Travel: Western trip (California, Oregon, Colorado, etc.), 1928-1929 (Box 23)
  - Travel: Western trip (California, Oregon, Colorado, etc.): NITRATES, 1928-1929 (Box 43)
  - Travel: Washington State, California, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Travel: Friday Harbor, California: scrapbook album, circa 1925-1926 (Box 42)
  - Travel: Friday Harbor, California: NITRATES, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 43)
  - Travel: California, circa 1960s (Box 23)
  - Travel: Northwest, circa 1960s (Box 23)
  - Travel: Nova Scotia, etc., circa 1960s (Box 23)
  - Travel: Southwest U.S., circa 1960s (Box 23)
  - Travel: Assorted locations, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 23)
  - Travel: Assorted locations: NITRATES, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 43)
- Local History Materials, 1792-1930
  - [Baptist Church?] minutes, 1792-1897 (Box 20)
  - Berkeley Co., W Va Miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - History of Old Berkeley by Ann H. Gardiner, undated (Box 21)
  - Hedgesville, W.Va. (Box 21)
  - Martinsburg, W.Va. (Box 21)
  - History of Martinsburg and Vicinity, 1778-1926 by Mabel Henshaw Gardiner (master's thesis), 1930 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 21)
  - Shepherdstown, W. Va. (Box 21)
  - Tuscarora Presbyterian Church (Box 21)
- Scrapbooks, 1882-1981
  - Miscellaneous (news clippings), 1882 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous (advertisements, scraps), ca. 1889 (Box 26)
  - Notebook (Robert Gardiner family), 1889-1970 (Box 26)
  - Notebook (Sheperd College, nurses training), 1891-1919, 1981, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Notebook (educational records), 1901-1974 (Box 27)
  - Notebook (nursing - WWI), May 1917-June 1918 (Box 28)
  - Notebook (nursing - WWI), June 1918-1919 (Box 28)
  - Notebook (miscellaneous), 1919-1940 (Box 29)
  - Notebook (nursing - Duke), 1930-1978 (Box 29)
  - Notebook (miscellaneous), 1930-1978 (Box 29)
  - Notebook (miscellaneous), 1941-1978 (Box 30)
  - Notebook (miscellaneous), 1966-1980 (Box 30)
  - Notebook (miscellaneous), 1979-1980 (Box 31)
- Clippings, Albums, School Work, Ephemera, and Nursing School Materials, circa 1790-1980; 1800-1930
  - Miscellaneous, 1871-1950s (Box 32)
  - Arithmetic ca. 1790-1791 (Box 32)
  - Autograph Albums (Mabel Henshaw and Fannie Henshaw), 1882-1888 (Box 32)
  - Clippings, 1908-1930, undated (Box 32)
  - Duke University School of Nursing, 1930-1940, 1980 (Box 32)
  - Duke University School of Nursing (clippings), 1935-1923 (Box 32)
  - Duke University School of Nursing (history), 1936 (Box 32)
  - Duke University School of Nursing (Gardiner portrait), 1980 (Box 32)
  - Duke University School of Nursing (speeches), 1939 - 1970, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Embryology notes, 1927 (Box 32)
  - Invitations, announcements, visiting cards, late 1800s-early 1900s (Box 32)
  - Recipes and remedies, 1800s (Box 33)
  - Red Cross nursing cap, 1917 (Box 33)
  - Writings, undated (Box 33)
  - Writings - The Chromatophones of Cetapods (thesis), 1896 (Box 33)
  - Writings - Development of the External Form of a Squid Embryo (thesis), 1927 (Box 33)
- Oversize Materials, 1754-1950
  General note
  (Note: photocopies of oversized materials are filed in corresponding series above)
  - Legal Papers - Deeds, 1754-1850 (Box 38)
  - Legal Papers - Land Office (Berkeley Co., W.Va), 1814-1819 (Box 38)
  - Legal Papers - Land Surveys (Berkeley Co., W.Va), 1790s-1826 (Box 38)
  - Legal Papers - Military, 1814 (Box 38)
  - Genealogical Materials - Henshaw family (DAR applications), undated (Box 38)
  - Local History Materials - [?] Baptist Church Minutes, 1792-1797 (Box 38)
  - Photographic Materials - Historical documents and buildings (prints), undated (Box 38)
  - Scrapbook (clippings), ca. mid-late 1800s (Box 38)
  - Certificates 1886-1950 (Box 38)
  - Deed 1819 (Box 38)
  - Copper plate with map of Berkeley County, Virginia, 1847 (Box 38)